

Igor Souza Web Developer

® Tijuca, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

⊠soujigor@gmail.com

%+5521996240029

SOCIAL

in @soujigor

@soujigor

@soujigor

PROFILE

As a self-taught front-end developer, I'm looking for a first time job at the field.

I've worked many years directly with the public, what made me confident, well spoken and sociable.

I also worked during the World Cup and Olympic Games, managing a tourist hostel in Rio de Janeiro, and I've been working as a freelance translator, therefore, I have an excellent writen and spoken English and Spanish.

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese
- English
- Spanish

EDUCATION

Web Developer

Self-taught (Udemy, Codecademy, freeCodeCamp) 2021 - present

Bachelor's Degree in History

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro - UFRJ 2010 - 2015

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Translator

From 2018 to present | Self Employed

- Translation experience in legal , scientific, commercial and education areas.
- Industry experience from automotive, financial services , pharma and legal.
- Trilingual in English and Spanish with Portuguese as native language.
- Hundreds of projects encompassing translation, transcreation and localization.
- Translated the widest possible range of documents, manuals and presentations.
- Experienced with all popular versions of translation software.
- Professional proofreading skills, allowing self-editing before submission.
- Unique quality assurance process that is taken from industry best practice.

Hostel Manager

From 2013 to 2018 | Ipanema Hostel Club, Alma de Santa Guest House, Che Lagarto Hostel

- Effectively led the execution of strategies as developed by leadership members.
- Promoted the hostel, its facilities, and its services.
- Assisted guests with reservation arrangements and special requests.
- Established databases and internal tracking systems to ensure accuracy of data.
- Recommended top dining and entertainment options for guests in all Rio de Janeiro.
- Oversaw a team of 15 hostel employees.
- Recruited and trained some new members of the guest service and cleaning team.

SKILLS

- React / React Native
- Firebase / Git
- Bootstrap / Chakra / Tailwind
- Node.js
- CSS / HTML / Figma
- Javascript / Typescript

INTERESTS









Music

Travel

Games

Readina